Eliott Brown

elilogbro@gmail.com

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in **Ruby on Rails and JavaScript** based programming with an affinity for **React**. Background in professional volunteer work, including disaster relief and leading crews on conservation-oriented projects. Possess strong technical and interpersonal skills that help companies maintain a positive work environment while implementing creative and quality code solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js, Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, Active Record, SQLite, Sinatra, Authentication, Styled Components, Object-Oriented Programming, MVC Frameworks, Object-Relational Mapping, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, CRUD, RESTful API, GitHub, VSCode

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Workout Tracker - GitHub | Demo

Workout tracking application that enables users to keep track of their workout history, edit or repeat old routines, and create a new routine.

- Developed custom serializer and controller methods to retrieve necessary backend data more efficiently
- Styled application using styled components to increase code modularity and reusability
- Utilized bcrypt password hashing and salting to secure user information from malicious attacks
- Incorporated useContext and useEffect hooks to handle global state information and asynchronous functions

Tento - GitHub | Demo

Campsite finder application that incorporates real-world data and Google's Maps JavaScript API, filter functionality, user authentication, as well as cookies and sessions.

- Implemented Google Maps API functionality, allowing users to easily search for campsites by state or area
- Utilized PostgreSQL and Ruby on Rails to maintain a relational database designed to easily access user and campsite data
- Incorporated bcrypt password hashing to secure user information
- Authenticated users using sessions and cookies to create a seamless login and signup experience

Guitar World - GitHub-Frontend | GitHub-Backend | Demo

Guitar store app that enables a user to create an account, browse guitars with filter functionality, see their order history and place orders in real-time.

- Modeled a custom database schema and REST API using Ruby models, Active Record CRUD operations, and Sinatra localhost
- Sent get, read, update, and post HTTP requests to Ruby/Sinatra/SQL backend, allowing users to create an account, make changes to their personal information, and add guitars to the store
- Maintained a state-held user, allowing for an individual to view/edit their personal account and order information

Playlist Mixer - GitHub | Demo

Playlist application for music lovers. A place where a user can create a playlist, browse by genre, add new songs, and add songs to a 'favorites' tab.

- Created a custom db.json backend to add data to application
- Practiced RESTful API development using get, patch, post, and delete HTTP requests to keep code consistent and readable
- Reused components as necessary to keep app readable for other developers and limit browser loading times
- Designed user interface using CSS flex-box to help maintain user experience when browser isn't full screen

EXPERIENCE

Flatiron School Remote

Software Engineering Immersive Student

7/2022 - 10/2022

- Formed a comprehensive knowledge of React library core concepts
- Gained knowledge and implementation of Ruby on Rails database management
- Utilized GitHub to manage source control repositories with multiple contributors
- **RESTful API** development and deployment
- Built full-stack applications with **VSCode**

Peloton InteractiveDenver, COField Specialist11/2020 - 02/2022

Provided safe, on-time, and dependable transportation with a safe driving record

- Received over 25 five star reviews, reflecting customer satisfaction after setup process
- Assisted customers during the set-up process with excellent customer service
- Performed basic stationary bike maintenance and troubleshooting in-home
- Remained flexible during the COVID-19 pandemic when inventory and scheduling were unknown

US Forest Service Minturn, CO
Ranger 5/2020 - 10/2020

- Educated the public on forest-use regulations
- Collaborated with other rangers to ensure all daily duties were accomplished
- Monitored visitor use and enforced warnings in campgrounds and day-use areas
- Performed preventative maintenance checks on the work vehicles once per month
- Frequently used a chainsaw for various projects (fencing, road clearing, trail clearing)

Southwest Conservation Corps

Salida, CO

Trail Crew Leader 4/2019 - 11/2019

- Managed crews on conservation-oriented projects, such as: trail maintenance and construction, fence removal, and invasive species removal
- Led a crew of six 18-25 year olds on nine day hitches in frontcountry and backcountry settings
- Planned all aspects of the project, including work schedule, travel, and meals
- Performed constructive evaluations on the crew and actively listened to feedback/evaluations for myself
- Helped to develop the crew's work-related and personal goals throughout the season

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

Full Stack Software Engineering: Ruby on Rails and React programming

7/2022 - 10/2022

Red Rocks Community College

Denver, CO

Courses: Humanities, English, Anthropology

1/2022 - 5/2022

GPA: 4.0